The Musical Event of the Holiday Season
Black Nativity is a music, drama film directed by Kasi Lemmons.
A street-wise teen from Baltimore who has been raised by a single mother travels to New York City to spend the
Christmas holiday with his estranged relatives, where he embarks on a surprising and inspirational journey.
Reverend Cornell Cobbs, played by Forest Whitaker.
Aretha Cobbs, played by Angela Bassett.
Naima, played by Jennifer Hudson.
Loot / Tyson, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Langston, played by Jacob Latimore.
Platinum Fro, played by Mary J. Blige.
Black Nativity is a 2013 American musical drama film written and directed by Kasi
Lemmons, based on Langston Hughes' 1961 play of the same name.
The film stars an ensemble cast, featuring Forest Whitaker, Angela
Bassett, Tyrese Gibson, Jennifer Hudson, Mary J.
Blige, Jacob Latimore, Vondie Curtis-Hall, and rapper Nas.
It was released in the United States on November 27,
2013, by Fox Searchlight Pictures.
The film explores themes of bible, musical, based on
play or musical, woman director, nativity.
The tone is emotional.